Guide to the Consumer Reports. George Arthur papers, 1987-2011 RL.11854
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Consumer Reports. George Arthur papers
1987-2011
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Consumer Reports (Firm)
RL.11854
0.4 Linear Feet
Consumer Reports is a product testing and consumer advocacy nonprofit organization based in Yonkers, N.Y., founded in 1936. George Arthur is Executive Design Director for the organization. The George Arthur papers include correspondence, design manuals, graphic design examples, organizational proposals and reports and other printed materials. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Arrangement
Organized alphabetically.
Biographical / Historical
Consumer Reports is a product testing and consumer advocacy nonprofit organization based in Yonkers, N.Y., founded in 1936. George Arthur is Executive Design Director for the organization.
George Arthur was associated with the School of Visual Arts from 1964-1967. Before joining Consumers Union in 1978 he worked as Designer and Art Director for a number of magazines (Life, On the Sound, Sport, Venture). From 1978 Arthur was Design Director at Consumers Union, working on both publication design and corporate identity standards including the current logo and typeface. In 2010 Arthur was named Executive Design Director.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The Consumer Reports. George Arthur papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2019.
Related Materials
Related materials may be found in the following Hartman Center collections:
Consumer Reports Archives records.
Consumer Reports. Iconographic materials
Consumer Reports. Editorial Department records.
Collection Overview
The George Arthur papers include correspondence, design manuals, graphic design examples, organizational proposals and reports and other printed materials.
Consumer advocacy; Consumer education; Graphic artists -- United States; Arthur, George; John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History
- Consumer Reports Stylebook, approximately 2004; 3 folders (Box 1)
- CR Magazine discussion, 2002 (Box 1)
- Decision Making at Consumers Union pocket guide, approximately 1995 (Box 1)
- Design Department: Adapting for the Future, 2004 (Box 1)
- Design Department: Increasing Our Photographic Facilities, 2006 (Box 1)
- Design Style Book, 1996 (Box 1)
- Graphic design examples, approximately 2000-2011 (Box 1)
- Guidelines for Editors and Publishers (American Society of Magazine Editors), 1999 (Box 1)
- Manual of Specifications, 1999 (Box 1)
- Memos, 1987-2010 (Box 1)
- Photo Expansion Project (Tony Freeman), 2006 (Box 1)
- Possible Configurations for the Donor Wall at Consumers Union, approximately 1995 (Box 1)